### MARGARET ANN PASKOWSKI

197 Kozani Street Bristol, CT 06010 Home: (860) 589-6263 Mobile: (860) 614-0691 marge.paskowski@hotmail.com

#### SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Highly motivated and personable professional with extensive corporate experience in both administrative and managerial backgrounds. Highly skilled in leadership, organizational dynamics and technical proficiency. Proven Team Leader with verifiable track record of producing results and achieving desired performance goals. Committed to excellence in pursuing new challenges and opportunities by utilizing my professional skills which will allow opportunities for further personal growth.

#### **KEY COMPETENCIES**

- Excellent interpersonal communication and verbal skills
- Expert in time management; very detail oriented
- Works well independently and as a team player
- Strong in PC skills (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Outlook, Lotus Notes)
- Extraordinary teambuilding and motivational talent
- Outstanding multi-tasking and prioritization skills
- Functions well in fast-paced business environment
- Exceptional work ethic

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# TUNXIS COMMUNITY COLLEGE - Farmington, CT

# Attending Classes ( Part Time)

2010 – Present

March, 2012 Fast Course Excel 2007 Level 2
February, 2012 Fast Course Excel 2007 Level 1
October, 2011 Microsoft Excel 2010 Intermediate
September, 2011 Microsoft Excel 2010 Beginner
January, 2011 Microsoft Excel 2007 Intermediate
September, 2010 Fast Track to Excel 2007
September, 2010 Microsoft PowerPoint 2007

# PRICEWATERHOUSECOOPERS LLP - Hartford, CT

#### **Expense Business & Travel Specialist**

2006 - 2010

- Responsible for operationalizing shared resource concept for expense processing
- Assumed lead position within EBTS unit consisting of four Specialists
- Supported 80+ internal staff by providing business travel coordination and expense processing
- Closely monitored expenses and prepared expense reports via Firm's Global Financial System (GFS)
- Interpreted the Firm's expense policies and ensured they were strictly enforced
- Built loyal and productive relationships with all clients from Partner to entry-level staff
- Reduced costs by up to 25% by utilizing lowest fares, preferred hotels and negotiated car services
- Reduced administrative costs by 10% by efficiently finalizing expense reports for staff
- Created concept of 'One Stop Shopping' by combining all relevant travel information within one database
- Responsible and held accountable for performing expense reconciliations
- Resolved fraud issues, corporate card suspensions, late payment penalties

#### **Executive Assistant Team Leader – Financial Services**

2000 - 2006

- Led 9-member, cross-departmental Executive Assistant (EA) Team
- Responsible for workload balancing, personnel management, conflict resolution among team members
- Acted as a negotiator with EA staff and higher management; set a positive role model
- Provided administrative support to National Higher Education Leader; significant exposure to senior level management at major universities/colleges across U.S.
- Supported 1 Partner, 3 Directors and 4 Senior Managers while simultaneously performing the responsibilities and duties of a Team Leader
- Conducted monthly team meetings; encouraged team participations in issues/resolutions
- Active team participation in charity organizations (Gifts of Love/Toys for Tots)
- Involved in special projects; large mass mailings, PowerPoint and financial statement presentations

### MARGARET ANN PASKOWSKI

# PRICEWATERHOUSECOOPERS LLP - Hartford, CT (Continued) **Executive Assistant: Financial Services – ABAS** 1998 - 2000Provided administrative support to 2 Partners and several staff members Heavy involvement in the unit's financial reporting system; included all client billings, time/expense reporting, WIPs (Work in Process) - Key player in the coordination/preparation and final submission of RFPs (Request for Proposals) **Administrative Assistant: International Taxes** 1997 - 1998 Coordinated and presented quarterly seminars (Global Tax Forums) sponsored by International Tax to clients and companies located across the Northeast - Heavy involvement in proposals to prospective clients regarding resolution of tax issues (i.e. mergers, acquisitions, international business expansions, tax shelters, etc.) Researched various tax rules and regulations within the Firm and by using outside sources Administrative Assistant: Insurance/Auditing 1996 – 1997 Reported directly to Partner of Insurance and Auditing sector - Coordinated all meetings, teleconferences and domestic/international travel Maintained log of continuing education credits (CPE) earned and CPA license and registrations Prepared financial statements, presentations, Audit Committee Quarterly/Closing reports AETNA LIFE & CASUALTY COMPANY - Hartford, CT **Executive Assistant: Strategic Markets & Products** 1995 - 1996Reported to Vice President and Head of Broker/Dealer Marketing; National Sales Manager and 12 wholesalers located across the U.S. - Organized and coordinated all formal staff meetings and complex teleconferences - Independently made decisions regarding budget issues; responsible in maintaining budget for 3 cost centers. Analyzed all costs/expenditures associated with each cost center - Authorized all vouchers and expense and travel reports on behalf of Vice President Handled all personnel issues (i.e. hiring/employee orientations/terminations) and employee profiles Extensive interaction with various brokers and dealers within Home Office and field Direct interaction with clients from various brokerage firms (i.e. Advest, Paine Webber, Legg Mason, Edward D. Jones and Federated Investors) **Administrative Assistant: Bond/Fidelity** 1989 - 1995 Supported Vice President, direct reports and staff within Property & Casualty department Strong emphasis on coordination of all internal/external business meetings, daily planning and scheduling of Vice President's calendar/appointments Exposure to sensitive personnel issues within department and in Human Resources Handled unit's budget, independently composed all written correspondence within office Responsible for office meeting minutes; utilized stenography and transcription skills UNITED TECHNOLOGIES CORPORATION - Farmington, CT HAMILTON STANDARD DIVISION 1981 - 1989

Production Method Procedures Coordinator Administrative Assistant - Chief of Manufacturing Senior Secretary to the Operations Manager Project Engineering Secretary

#### **EDUCATION**

Central Connecticut State University - B.S. Business Administration (Marketing/Management) - Graduation: December, 2013

BayPath College - Successfully completed; awarded the Certified Professional Secretarial (CPS) designation

Member of NAESAA (National Association of Executive Secretaries & Administrative Assistants)